<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>preaction</title>
        <link>http://preaction.me/blog/tag/community/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/community.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>Blog feed of preaction</description>
        <generator>Statocles 0.085</generator>
        <item>
            <title>Technology Never Dies</title>
            <link>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/12/03/technology-never-dies/</link>
            <guid>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/12/03/technology-never-dies/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <div>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">List of things unpopular with programmers that I enjoy and
have produced valuable solutions with:<br>1) Perl<br>2) JavaScript<br>3)
C++<br>4) Excel<br>5) Java<br>6) CSS<br><br>Give it a month and I&#39;ll
have another one for the list... Popularity contests are for
small-minded people.</p>— Presistance (@preaction) <a href="https://twitter.com/preaction/status/936352187004878849?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November
30, 2017</a></blockquote><script async charset="utf-8" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script> 
</div>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/preaction/status/936352187004878849">This tweet got a lot of likes and
replies</a>, so
I should expand on it a bit.  Most of the replies were additions to the
list: Visual Basic (tool for automating and scripting Windows),
Microsoft Access (great for small databases), PHP (which unseated Perl
as the powerhouse of the web). But some of the replies were the things
I deal with a lot: Explanations why my choices suck and I should choose
other things.</p>

<p>I&#39;m mature, experienced, and confident enough so that now those things
don&#39;t bother me, but it&#39;s a problem for novices in the tech community.
Learning is difficult and frustrating, and hearing that the effort taken
to learn a technology is worthless because that technology is &quot;bad&quot; is
demoralizing and can lead to people leaving tech altogether.</p>

<p>So, let me help you cut off some of these discussions:</p>

<h2>X is Dead</h2>

<ul>
<li>X is obsolete</li>
<li>X is outdated</li>
<li>X is dying</li>
<li>X is dead</li>
</ul>

<p>No, it isn&#39;t. Technologies don&#39;t die easily, and I can assure you that
once a technology has left the technology journalism circuit it will
continue still for quite some time.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortran">FORTRAN</a>, one of the oldest computer languages, still has new
projects being written in it, and indeed had a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortran#Fortran_2008">new specification come
out in 2008</a> which adds concurrency and a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortran#Fortran_2018">new spec being planned
for 2018</a>.</li>
<li>New games are being written for the
<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/9/15584416/new-games-retro-consoles-nes-snes-sega-genesis-famicom">NES</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/11/26/3693208/c64-indie-games-paul-koller">Commodore 64</a>, and
<a href="https://atariage.com">Atari 2600</a>.</li>
<li>Flash is still ubiquitous, despite being declared dead in 2007.</li>
<li>Operating systems abandoned by their parent companies (or whose parent
companies are dead) still have devoted communities, and even active
development (BeOS is now <a href="https://www.haiku-os.org">Haiku</a>, Solaris
has <a href="https://wiki.illumos.org/display/illumos/illumos+Home">Illumos</a>,
and even Windows XP has <a href="https://reactos.org">ReactOS</a>).</li>
</ul>

<p>What they might mean is &quot;X is no longer a way to be successful&quot;, which is also
mostly false depending on how you measure success: If you want to make VC
money, that is probably true. If you want to learn about technology or solve
problems using technology, it is entirely false. If you want to make a career
in technology, it&#39;s certainly false: Even old technology needs support,
maintenance, and development.</p>

<p>What they might also mean is &quot;X is no longer the only technology that can solve
its specific problem&quot;, and that&#39;s a good thing. Technology evolves when it is
exposed to new ideas, and there&#39;s no better way to get exposed to new ideas
than to compete with other technology. This is why FORTRAN has a new spec
coming out, as well as languages like Ada and COBOL.</p>

<p>&quot;X is dead&quot; is anti-marketing. Don&#39;t be taken in.</p>

<h2>X is Bad</h2>

<ul>
<li>X is ugly</li>
<li>X is unmaintainable</li>
<li>X is terrible</li>
<li>X considered harmful</li>
<li>X is bad</li>
</ul>

<p>Technology is invented at a specific time for a specific purpose. There aren&#39;t
many technologies that gain widespread acceptance while being unsuitable for
their purposes. So, how can that surviving technology be entirely bad?</p>

<p>What they almost always mean is &quot;X is bad to use now&quot;, and that&#39;s also often
false: While there may be more and better solutions to the particular problem
(which, as explained above, is a good thing), a surviving technology often
still has niches where it fits better than any other. This does mean that you
need to do your research: Look at the problem domain, find the solutions, and
if you have time, try them out to see which one you like better. Don&#39;t let &quot;X
is bad&quot; stop you from trying X out to see if it solves your problem.</p>

<p>What they may also mean is &quot;X teaches bad things&quot;, which is vehemently false:
Learning about the history of a technology is important. Learning about
historical problems and solutions is important. Technology is built for a
reason. Learning those reasons will explain the design decisions made. Learning
about design decisions and tradeoffs can teach you how to proceed when nothing
is a good option. No technology is built to be deliberately terrible (though
some technologies are certainly satirical or farcical, they are excellent
satire/farce and should be evaluated as such, like INTERCAL).</p>

<p>I have, in fact, learned the most from learning other languages designs.
Java taught me a lot about OO, which I brought in to all my programs.
Using pthreads in C++ taught me a lot about process safety and
message-passing, which I then started using <a href="http://zeromq.org">Zeromq</a>
to solve for me (when I can, but I still know how to solve that problem
without if needed). The more shell scripting I learn, the less work
I end up having to do (fact). Shell taught me fantastic lessons about
composability of programs that I never thought possible, and I’ve got
some projects that take full advantage of that.</p>

<p>&quot;X is bad&quot; is almost always a disingenuous attempt to get you to use their
favorite technology. Don&#39;t be fooled!</p>

<p>Technology is not a popularity contest. Technology is not good because it&#39;s
popular, and it&#39;s not bad because it is unpopular. Technology is not good
because its unique, and it&#39;s not bad because it exists in a crowded maze of
solutions, all alike. We need to evaluate technology objectively and
critically, whether popular or unpopular. And we must always remember to be
kind to people using technology.</p>

                    <p><a href="http://preaction.me/blog/2017/12/03/technology-never-dies/#section-2">Continue reading...</a></p>
                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/software/">software</a>
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/community/">community</a>
                </p>
            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>
                Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nerds Rejecting Nerds</title>
            <link>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/04/23/nerds-rejecting-nerds/</link>
            <guid>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/04/23/nerds-rejecting-nerds/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <p><a href="https://medium.com/@maradydd/when-nerds-collide-31895b01e68c">https://medium.com/@maradydd/when-nerds-collide-31895b01e68c</a></p>

<p>I was linked to this article after a discussion that was triggered by
a Tweet: <a href="https://twitter.com/shadowcat_mst/status/852265380156510214">https://twitter.com/shadowcat_mst/status/852265380156510214</a></p>

<p>In this article, the author describes a group called &quot;weird nerds&quot;,
later renamed &quot;hackers&quot;, and goes through some of the reasons why this
group is rejecting new members of their community (namely &quot;brogrammers&quot;
and &quot;geek feminists&quot;, a false equivalence if ever there was one).</p>

<p>As someone who fits the author&#39;s idea of a hacker (the classical
definition of hacker, not someone who breaks into computers), and yet
has never felt like part of the hacker community, there are a lot of
things in here that are bad, but I&#39;ll comment for now on a couple
quotes:</p>

                    <p><a href="http://preaction.me/blog/2017/04/23/nerds-rejecting-nerds/#section-2">Continue reading...</a></p>
                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/community/">community</a>
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/feminism/">feminism</a>
                </p>
            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>
                Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Community is a Reflection of its Leaders</title>
            <link>http://preaction.me/blog/2016/02/15/a-community-is-a-reflection-of-its-leaders/</link>
            <guid>http://preaction.me/blog/2016/02/15/a-community-is-a-reflection-of-its-leaders/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <p>I&#39;ve been in charge of <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/2016/02/15/a-community-is-a-reflection-of-its-leaders/#footnote-1">a certain community</a> for a very
long time. Before my actual tech career started, even. Back when doing
websites was just a hobby I didn&#39;t want to ruin by getting money
involved.</p>

<p>I was put in charge of this community after only a few hours of effort:
I wanted to learn something, I saw that a community didn&#39;t exist for
this topic in some prime community real estate, and so I created one.
Instantly, I was the leader of a community. Within weeks, people started
pouring in.</p>

<p>The funny thing about being in charge of a community is that it doesn&#39;t
require merit or community-building skills. Being in charge of
a community merely requires that one have authority: The ability to
decide who is part of the community and who is not. Because I founded
the community, I had the authority.</p>

                    <p><a href="http://preaction.me/blog/2016/02/15/a-community-is-a-reflection-of-its-leaders/#section-2">Continue reading...</a></p>
                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/community/">community</a>
                </p>
            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>
                Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>

