<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>http://preaction.me/blog/tag/racism/</id>
    <title>preaction</title>
    <updated>2016-07-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <link href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/racism.atom" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/racism/" rel="alternate" />
    <generator version="0.081">Statocles</generator>
    <entry>
        <id>http://preaction.me/blog/2016/07/08/what-history-class-did-you-fail-/</id>
        <title>What History Class Did You Fail?</title>
        <link href="http://preaction.me/blog/2016/07/08/what-history-class-did-you-fail-/" rel="alternate" />
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
            <p>Every time I’m involved in some social media discussion, I hear so much
completely inaccurate information being repeated time and again. Today,
someone claimed that people in South Africa would have “Black
Privilege”, completely ignorant of the long history of violent white
supremacy that ended less than 30 years ago. Additionally, way too many
people are ignorant of Jim Crow, and all the things that led up to and
followed the 1960’s Civil Rights Movement.</p>

<p>Ignoring the history of race relations is the foundation of a generation
of future racists. This complete ignorance of the past, this
white-washing, this idea that “racism ended in 1964 with the Civil
Rights Act”, these ideas are the start of a belief that the current race
relation problem is “reverse racism”: White people being discriminated
against. And since anti-Black racism is “over”, all the crime statistics
that show problems disproportionately affecting Black people must mean
that Black people are “just naturally like that.”</p>

<p>Curiously, these people are always well-“informed” about the history of
slavery world-wide, but never about how the Americas changed all that,
too. Indentured servitude is not chattel slavery, but the distinction is
both lost and meaningless to those who want to believe that global
racism ended with the abolition of slavery in the US. And again, the
bleaching of history: The Civil War was about state’s rights, despite
the libraries of information written at the time on the topic about the
war’s aims.</p>

<p>It has taken me mere months of casual perusal to learn the things that
I know, or, more accurately, probe the vastness of the chasm that is my
ignorance. With all the current news about racial violence, what hope
for change can there be if we aren’t all putting in this minimum amount
of effort to understand our fellow humans?</p>

                <p><a href="http://preaction.me/blog/2016/07/08/what-history-class-did-you-fail-/#section-2">Continue reading...</a></p>
            <p>Tags:
                <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/racism/">racism</a>
                <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/history/">history</a>
                <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/blacklivesmatter/">blacklivesmatter</a>
            </p>
        ]]></content>
        <updated>2016-07-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <category term="racism" />
        <category term="history" />
        <category term="blacklivesmatter" />
    </entry>
</feed>

