<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>preaction</title>
        <link>http://preaction.me/blog/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://preaction.me/blog/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>Blog feed of preaction</description>
        <generator>Statocles 0.085</generator>
        <item>
            <title>Technology Never Dies</title>
            <link>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/12/03/technology-never-dies/</link>
            <guid>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/12/03/technology-never-dies/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <div>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">List of things unpopular with programmers that I enjoy and
have produced valuable solutions with:<br>1) Perl<br>2) JavaScript<br>3)
C++<br>4) Excel<br>5) Java<br>6) CSS<br><br>Give it a month and I&#39;ll
have another one for the list... Popularity contests are for
small-minded people.</p>— Presistance (@preaction) <a href="https://twitter.com/preaction/status/936352187004878849?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November
30, 2017</a></blockquote><script async charset="utf-8" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script> 
</div>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/preaction/status/936352187004878849">This tweet got a lot of likes and
replies</a>, so
I should expand on it a bit.  Most of the replies were additions to the
list: Visual Basic (tool for automating and scripting Windows),
Microsoft Access (great for small databases), PHP (which unseated Perl
as the powerhouse of the web). But some of the replies were the things
I deal with a lot: Explanations why my choices suck and I should choose
other things.</p>

<p>I&#39;m mature, experienced, and confident enough so that now those comments
don&#39;t bother me, but it&#39;s a problem for novices in the tech community.
Learning is difficult and frustrating, and hearing that the effort taken
to learn a technology is worthless because that technology is &quot;bad&quot; is
demoralizing and can lead to people leaving tech altogether.</p>

<p>So, let me help you cut off some of these discussions:</p>

<h2>X is Dead</h2>

<ul>
<li>X is obsolete</li>
<li>X is outdated</li>
<li>X is dying</li>
<li>X is dead</li>
</ul>

<p>No, it isn&#39;t. Technologies don&#39;t die easily, and I can assure you that
once a technology has left the technology journalism circuit it will
continue still for quite some time.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortran">FORTRAN</a>, one of the oldest computer languages, still has new
projects being written in it, and indeed had a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortran#Fortran_2008">new specification come
out in 2008</a> which adds concurrency and a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortran#Fortran_2018">new spec being planned
for 2018</a>.</li>
<li>New games are being written for the
<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/9/15584416/new-games-retro-consoles-nes-snes-sega-genesis-famicom">NES</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/11/26/3693208/c64-indie-games-paul-koller">Commodore 64</a>, and
<a href="https://atariage.com">Atari 2600</a>.</li>
<li>Flash is still ubiquitous, despite being <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPhone_(1st_generation)">declared dead in
2007</a>.</li>
<li>Operating systems abandoned by their parent companies (or whose parent
companies are dead) still have devoted communities, and even active
development (BeOS is now <a href="https://www.haiku-os.org">Haiku</a>, Solaris
has <a href="https://wiki.illumos.org/display/illumos/illumos+Home">Illumos</a>,
and even Windows XP has <a href="https://reactos.org">ReactOS</a>).</li>
</ul>

<p>What they might mean is &quot;X is no longer a way to be successful&quot;, which is also
mostly false depending on how you measure success: If you want to make VC
money, that is probably true. If you want to learn about technology or solve
problems using technology, it is entirely false. If you want to make a career
in technology, it&#39;s certainly false: Even old technology needs support,
maintenance, and development.</p>

<p>What they might also mean is &quot;X is no longer the only technology that can solve
its specific problem&quot;, and that&#39;s a good thing. Technology evolves when it is
exposed to new ideas, and there&#39;s no better way to get exposed to new ideas
than to compete with other technology. This is why FORTRAN has a new spec
coming out, as well as languages like Ada and COBOL.</p>

<p>&quot;X is dead&quot; is anti-marketing. Don&#39;t be taken in.</p>

<h2>X is Bad</h2>

<ul>
<li>X is ugly</li>
<li>X is unmaintainable</li>
<li>X is terrible</li>
<li>X considered harmful</li>
<li>X is bad</li>
</ul>

<p>Technology is invented at a specific time for a specific purpose. There aren&#39;t
many technologies that gain widespread acceptance while being unsuitable for
their purposes. So, how can that surviving technology be entirely bad?</p>

<p>What they almost always mean is &quot;X is bad to use now&quot;, and that&#39;s also often
false: While there may be more and better solutions to the particular problem
(which, as explained above, is a good thing), a surviving technology often
still has niches where it fits better than any other. This does mean that you
need to do your research: Look at the problem domain, find the solutions, and
if you have time, try them out to see which one you like better. Don&#39;t let &quot;X
is bad&quot; stop you from trying X out to see if it solves your problem.</p>

<p>What they may also mean is &quot;X teaches bad things&quot;, which is vehemently false:
Learning about the history of a technology is important. Learning about
historical problems and solutions is important. Technology is built for a
reason. Learning those reasons will explain the design decisions made. Learning
about design decisions and tradeoffs can teach you how to proceed when nothing
is a good option. No technology is built to be deliberately terrible (though
some technologies are certainly satirical or farcical, they are excellent
satire/farce and should be evaluated as such, like INTERCAL).</p>

<p>I have, in fact, learned the most from learning other languages designs.
Java taught me a lot about OO, which I brought in to all my programs.
Using pthreads in C++ taught me a lot about process safety and
message-passing, which I then started using <a href="http://zeromq.org">Zeromq</a>
to solve for me (when I can, but I still know how to solve that problem
without if needed). The more shell scripting I learn, the less work
I end up having to do (fact). Shell taught me fantastic lessons about
composability of programs that I never thought possible, and I’ve got
some projects that take full advantage of that.</p>

<p>&quot;X is bad&quot; is almost always a disingenuous attempt to get you to use their
favorite technology. Don&#39;t be fooled!</p>

<p>Technology is not a popularity contest. Technology is not good because it&#39;s
popular, and it&#39;s not bad because it is unpopular. Technology is not good
because its unique, and it&#39;s not bad because it exists in a crowded maze of
solutions, all alike. We need to evaluate technology objectively and
critically, whether popular or unpopular. And we must always remember to be
kind to people using technology.</p>

                    <p><a href="http://preaction.me/blog/2017/12/03/technology-never-dies/#section-2">Continue reading...</a></p>
                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/software/">software</a>
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/community/">community</a>
                </p>
            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>
                Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>CPAN Testers at meta::hack v2</title>
            <link>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/11/29/cpan-testers-at-meta-hack-v2/</link>
            <guid>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/11/29/cpan-testers-at-meta-hack-v2/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <p>Two weeks ago, I was invited to <a href="https://metacpan.org/about/meta_hack">meta::hack v2, the second annual
MetaCPAN hackathon</a>. As the
primary maintainer of <a href="http://cpantesters.org">CPAN Testers</a>, I went to
continue improving the integration of CPAN Testers data with MetaCPAN
and generally improve the performance of CPAN Testers to the benefit of
the entire <a href="http://perl.org">Perl</a> ecosystem.</p>

                    <p><a href="http://preaction.me/blog/2017/11/29/cpan-testers-at-meta-hack-v2/#section-2">Continue reading...</a></p>
                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/perl/">perl</a>
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/cpantesters/">cpantesters</a>
                </p>
            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>
                Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Help CPAN Testers During meta::hack v2</title>
            <link>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/11/05/help-cpan-testers-during-meta-hack-v2/</link>
            <guid>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/11/05/help-cpan-testers-during-meta-hack-v2/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <p>Would you like to help <a href="http://cpantesters.org">CPAN Testers</a> during
<a href="http://www.olafalders.com/2017/10/12/announcing-metahack-v2/">meta::hack
v2</a>? <a href="https://chat.mibbit.com/?channel=%23cpantesters-discuss&amp;server=irc.perl.org">Join
us on IRC in #cpantesters-discuss on
irc.perl.org</a>,
<a href="https://lists.perl.org/list/cpan-testers-discuss.html">join our mailing list on
lists.perl.org</a>,
or e-mail me directly at <a href="mailto:doug@preaction.me">doug@preaction.me</a>.</p>

<p>With <a href="http://www.olafalders.com/2017/10/12/announcing-metahack-v2/">meta::hack
v2</a> only
two weeks away, I’ve written down my todo list for the hackathon. With
another brand-new machine graciously provided by
<a href="https://www.bytemark.co.uk">ByteMark</a>, who have been hosting CPAN
Testers for years, this year’s hackathon will involve more devops tasks
to improve reliability and stability of the various parts of the
project.</p>

<p>The new server will be the host for <a href="http://github.com/cpan-testers/cpantesters-backend">CPAN Testers backend
processes</a>, the
processes that turn the raw incoming data into the various reports used
by the websites and downstream systems. It will also be the new home for
the <a href="http://cpan.org">CPAN</a> and <a href="http://backpan.perl.org">BackPAN</a>
mirrors that CPAN Testers uses for data, and provides to external users
as part of <a href="http://mirrors.cpan.org">CPAN’s mirrors list</a>.</p>

                    <p><a href="http://preaction.me/blog/2017/11/05/help-cpan-testers-during-meta-hack-v2/#section-2">Continue reading...</a></p>
                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/cpantesters/">cpantesters</a>
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/perl/">perl</a>
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/hackathon/">hackathon</a>
                </p>
            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>
                Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>I Believe Men Can Be Better</title>
            <link>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/11/02/i-believe-men-can-be-better/</link>
            <guid>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/11/02/i-believe-men-can-be-better/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <p>I said <a href="https://twitter.com/preaction/status/923937942388822017">&quot;I believe men can be better&quot; last week regarding a job ad I was
reading</a>, and I&#39;ve
been thinking that this is a thing I&#39;ve rarely heard from anyone. I hear, all
the time, aphorisms disparaging men and removing all agency and blame for bad
behavior:</p>

<ul>
<li>&quot;Boys will be boys&quot;</li>
<li>&quot;That&#39;s just how guys are&quot;</li>
<li>&quot;You should have known that would happen -- he&#39;s a guy&quot;</li>
</ul>

<p>Growing up, I expected to be a terrible person. I expected to be
uncontrollable. I expected to want to hurt people. And I didn&#39;t want to be that
person. When I didn&#39;t become that person, I still knew that was what people
expected of me.</p>

<p>So, through the power of stereotype threat, a shy, sensitive boy turns into a
sullen, introverted man who struggles with depression. Because nobody ever told
him that men could be better.</p>

<p>And, through the magic of stereotype excuses, sexual predators occupy our
highest offices and control our most powerful institutions. Because nobody ever
told them that men had to be better.</p>

                    <p><a href="http://preaction.me/blog/2017/11/02/i-believe-men-can-be-better/#section-2">Continue reading...</a></p>
                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/feminism/">feminism</a>
                </p>
            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>
                Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Application Metrics with Yertl</title>
            <link>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/10/18/application-metrics-with-yertl/</link>
            <guid>http://preaction.me/blog/2017/10/18/application-metrics-with-yertl/</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <p>A time series database is a massively useful tool for system reporting
and monitoring. By storing series of simple values attached to
timestamps, an ops team can see how fast their application is
processing data, how much traffic they&#39;re serving, and how many
resources they&#39;re consuming. From this data they can determine how well
their application is working, track down issues in the system, and plan
for future resource needs.</p>

<p>There have been a lot of new databases and tools developed to create,
store, and consume time series data, and existing databases are being
enhanced to better support time series data.</p>

<p>With the new release of <a href="http://preaction.me/yertl">ETL::Yertl</a>, we can
easily translate SQL database queries into metrics for monitoring and
reporting. I&#39;ve been using these new features to monitor the <a href="http://cpantesters.org">CPAN
Testers</a> application.</p>

                    <p><a href="http://preaction.me/blog/2017/10/18/application-metrics-with-yertl/#section-2">Continue reading...</a></p>
                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/yertl/">yertl</a>
                    <a href="http://preaction.me/blog/tag/devops/">devops</a>
                </p>
            ]]></description>
            <pubDate>
                Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>

